{"questions":[{"question":"Part of the Harris and Gasshypothesis about the Red Sea rift would be weakened if it could be demonstrated that the composition of upper rock layers","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"cannot cause a suture to develop"},{"key":"B","answer":"has no effect onwhere a suture will occur"},{"key":"C","answer":"cannot provide information about the nature of underlying rocks"},{"key":"D","answer":"is similar on the two sides of a rift unless a suture divides the two sides"},{"key":"E","answer":"is usually different from the composition of underlying rocks"}],"right":["C"],"parent":0},{"question":"It can be inferred from the passage that the \"Other geologists\" (line 8) would be most likely to agree with which of the following statements?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"Similar geological features along both sides of a possible suture imply the existence of that suture"},{"key":"B","answer":"Sutures can be discovered only where they are not obscured by superimposed geological features."},{"key":"C","answer":"The composition of igneous rocks permits prediction of the likelihood of a rift developing through them."},{"key":"D","answer":"It is possible to date igneous rocks by carefully studying the different kinds of rare metals contained in them and by observing their similarity to the layer of rock that lies above them."},{"key":"E","answer":"The existence of rock layers on one side of a rift that are similar in composition to rock layers on the other side suggests that no suture exists between the two sides."}],"right":["E"],"parent":0},{"question":"It can be inferred from the passage that Harris and Gass have done which of the following?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"Drawn detailed diagrams of the Red Sea rift."},{"key":"B","answer":"Based their conclusions on the way in which sutures develop in the Earth's crust."},{"key":"C","answer":"Rejected other geologists objections to their hypothesis about the Red Sea rift."},{"key":"D","answer":"Suggested that the presence of rare metals in rocks indicates an underlying suture."},{"key":"E","answer":"Asserted that rifts usually occur along the lines of sutures"}],"right":["C"],"parent":0},{"question":"According to the passage, Harris and Gass have mentioned all of the following properties of rocks along the Red Sea rift EXCEPT","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"age of the upper layers of rock"},{"key":"B","answer":"structure of the upper layers of rocks"},{"key":"C","answer":"geochemical content of the upper layers of rocks"},{"key":"D","answer":"metallic content of the underlying igneous rocks"},{"key":"E","answer":"age of the underlying igneous rocks"}],"right":["E"],"parent":0},{"question":"The primary purpose of the passage is to","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"discuss the place of Coltrane in the world of jazz and describe his musical explorations"},{"key":"B","answer":"examine the nature of bebop and contrast it with improvisational jazz"},{"key":"C","answer":"analyze the musical sources of Coltrane's style and their influence on his work"},{"key":"D","answer":"acknowledge the influence of Coltrane's music on rock music and rock musicians"},{"key":"E","answer":"discuss the arguments that divide the proponents of different jazz styles"}],"right":["A"],"parent":1},{"question":"The author implies that which of the following would have been an effect of Coltrane's having chosen to play the tenor rather than the soprano saxophone on My Favorite Things?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"The tone of the recording would have been more somber."},{"key":"B","answer":"The influence of bebop on the recording would have been more obvious"},{"key":"C","answer":"The music on the recording would have sounded less raucous and physical"},{"key":"D","answer":"His influence on rock music might have been less pervasive."},{"key":"E","answer":"The style of the recording would have been indistinguishable from that on Kind of Blue"}],"right":["A"],"parent":1},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the organization of the fourth paragraph?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"A thesis referred to earlier in the passage is mentioned and illustrated with three specific examples "},{"key":"B","answer":"A thesis is stated and three examples are given each suggesting that a correction needs to be made to a thesis referred to earlier in the passage"},{"key":"C","answer":"A thesis referred to earlier in the passage is mentioned, and three examples are presented and ranked in order of their support of the thesis."},{"key":"D","answer":"A thesis is stated, three seemingly opposing examples are presented, and their underlying correspondence is explained"},{"key":"E","answer":"A thesis is stated, three dissimilar examples are considered, and the thesis is restated."}],"right":["A"],"parent":1},{"question":"According to the passage, John Coltrane did all of the following during his careerEXCEPT","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"improvise on melodies from a number of different cultures"},{"key":"B","answer":"perform as leader as well as soloist"},{"key":"C","answer":"spendtime improving his technical skills"},{"key":"D","answer":"experiment with the sounds of various instruments"},{"key":"E","answer":"eliminate the influence of bebop on his own music"}],"right":["E"],"parent":1},{"question":"The author mentions the work of Ornette Coleman in the fourth paragraph in order to do which of the following?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"Expand the discussion by mentioning the work of a saxophone player who played in Coltrane's style."},{"key":"B","answer":"Compare Coltrane's solos with the work of another jazz artist."},{"key":"C","answer":"Support the idea that rational organizing principles need to be applied to artistic work ."},{"key":"D","answer":"Show the increasing intricacy of Coltrane's work after he abandoned bebop"},{"key":"E","answer":"Indicate disagreement with the way Coltrane modulated the motifs in his lengthy solos."}],"right":["B"],"parent":1},{"question":"According to the passage, a major difference between Coltrane and other jazz musicians was the","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"degree to which Coltrane's music encompassed all of jazz"},{"key":"B","answer":"repetition of motifs that Coltrane used in his solos"},{"key":"C","answer":"number of his own compositions that Coltrane recorded"},{"key":"D","answer":"indifference Coltrane maintained to musical technique"},{"key":"E","answer":"importance Coltrane placed on rhythm in jazz"}],"right":["A"],"parent":1},{"question":"In terms of its tone and form, the passage can best be characterized as","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"dogmatic explanation "},{"key":"B","answer":"indignant denial"},{"key":"C","answer":"enthusiastic praise"},{"key":"D","answer":"speculative study "},{"key":"E","answer":"lukewarm review"}],"right":["C"],"parent":1}],"parent":["Geologists Harris and Gass hypothesized that the Red\nSea rift developed along the line of a suture (a splice in the\nEarth's crust) formed during the late Proterozoic era, and\nthat significant observable differences in the composition of\n(5)the upper layers of rocks deposited on either side of the\nsuture give clues to the different natures ofthe underlying\nigneous rocks.\n    Other geologists argued that neither the upper rock layer\nnor the underlying igneous rocks on the one side of the rift\n(10)differ fundamentally from the corresponding layers on the\nother side. These geologists believe, therefore, thatthere is\ninadequate evidence to conclude that a suture underlies the\nrift.\n    In response, Harris and Gass asserted that the upper rock\n(15)layers on the two sides of the rift had not been shownto be\nof similar age, structure, or geochemical content. Furthermore, \nthey cited new evidence that the underlyingigneous\nrocks on either side of the rift contain significantly different\nkinds of rare metals.","Proponents of different jazz styles have always argued\nthat their predecessors,musical style did not include\nessential characteristics that define jazz as jazz. Thus,\n1940's swing was belittled by beboppers of the 1950's,\n(5)whowere themselves attacked by free jazzers of the\n1960's. The neoboppers of the 1980's and 1990's attacked\nalmost everybody else. Thetitanic figure of Black saxophonist \nJohn Coltrane has complicated the arguments made\nby proponents of styles from bebop through neobop\n(10)because in his own musical journey he drew from all those\nstyles.His influence on all types of jazz was immeasurable.\nAt the height of his popularity, Coltrane largely abandoned\nplaying bebop, the style that had brought him fame, to\nexplore the outer reaches of jazz.\n(15) Coltrane himself probably believed that the only essential\ncharacteristic of jazz was improvisation, the one constant\nin his journey from bebop to open-ended improvisations on\nmodal, Indian, and African melodies. On the other hand,\nthis dogged student and prodigious technicianâ€”who\n(20)insisted on spending hours each day practicing scalesfrom\ntheory books-was never able to jettison completely the\ninfluence of bebop, with its fast and elaborate chains of\nnotes and ornaments on melody.\n Two stylistic characteristics shaped the way Coltrane\n(25)played the tenor saxophone, he favored playing fast runs\nofnotes built on a melody and depended on heavy, regularly \naccented beats. The first led Coltrane to \"sheets of\nsound.\" where he raced faster and faster, pile-driving notes\ninto each other to suggest stacked harmonies. The second\n(30)meantthat his sense of rhythm was almost as close to rock\nas to bebop.\n Three recordings illustrate Coltrane's energizing explorations. \n Recording Kind of Bluewith Miles Davis, Coltrane\nfound himself outside bop, exploring modal melodies. Here\n(35)he played surging, lengthy solos built largelyaround\nrepeated motifs-an organizing principle unlike that of\nfree jazz saxophone player Ornette Coleman, whomodulated or \naltered melodies in his solos. On Giant Steps,\nColtrane debuted as leader, introducing his owncomposi-\n(40)tions. Here the sheets of sound, downbeat accents, repetitions, \nand great speed are part of each solo, and the\nvariety of the shapes of his phrases is unique. Coltrane's\nsearching explorations produced solid achievement. My\nFavorite Thingswas another kind of watershed. Here\n(45)Coltrane played the soprano saxophone, an instrument\nseldom used by jazz musicians. Musically, the results were\nastounding. With the soprano's piping sound,ideas that had\nsounded dark and brooding acquired a feeling of giddy\nfantasy.\n(50) When Coltrane began recording for the Impulse! label,\nhe was still searching. His music became raucous, physical.\nHis influence on rockers was enormous,including Jimi\nHendrix, the rock guitarist, who following Coltrane, raised\nthe extended guitar solo using repeated motifs to a kind of\nrock art form"]}